George List papers, 1894-2008 C424
Indiana University Archives
- Correspondence and subject files, 1933-2008; undated (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence and subject files, 1933-2004; undated (Box 3)
    - Katzarova, Raina, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Kauffman, Christopher, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
    - Kaufman, Howard K., 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    - Kaufman, Walter, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Kim, Miss Chung-ja, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Kinney, Sylvia, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Klinge, Paul, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
    - Kolinski, Mieczyslaw, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - Kondo, Wyojiro, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Krader, Barbara, 1966-1978 (Box 4)
    - Krader, 1977 (Box 4)
    - L, 1957-1988 (Box 4)
    - Laade, Wolfgang, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Latin American Studies, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Lazan, Albert, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Leach, MacEdward, 1959-1963 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Dorothy S., 1978 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Hye-Ku, 1958 (Box 4)
    - Letters, Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Library, 1968-1975 (Box 4)
    - Library of Congress, 1955-1961 (Box 4)
    - List, Ace, 1976-1990 (Box 4)
    - List, Mandie, 1985-1994 (Box 4)
    - List, Mandie, Letters to, 1988-1992 (Box 4)
    - List, Michael (Box 4)
      - 1967-1975 (Box 4)
      - 1978-1991 (Box 4)
      - Activities outside of school, 1956-1967 (Box 4)
      - Birthday Greetings, undated (Box 4)
      - Grade School, Nursery School, 1952-1964 (Box 4)
      - Jr. and Sr. H.S., 1958-1966 (Box 4)
      - Letter from George, 1967-1970 (Box 4)
      - Letter from Mike, 1960 (Box 4)
      - Letter to HT Demonstration Faculty Material, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      - Letters, 1958-1976 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956-1966 (Box 4)
      - Note to Eve (List) on her last Mother's Day, 1999 (Box 4)
      - University I - IU, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, 1982-1988 (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, Charlie (Box 4)
      - 1939-1976 (Box 4)
      - 1948-1969 (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, El (in German), undated (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, Marian, 2000s (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, Max - George's Father's Funeral, undated (Box 4)
    - Lisitsky, Max and Molly, 1949-1960 (Box 4)
    - List Library (Box 4)
      - 1976-1979, undated (Box 4)
      - 1981 (Box 4)
    - Love, Jacob and Corollary Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - Love Materials, Ogalic Courses, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Mc (Box 4)
      - 1962-1981 (Box 4)
      - 1978-1983 (Box 4)
    - McAllester, David P. (Box 4)
      - 1959-1975 (Box 4)
      - 1981-1991 (Box 4)
    - McCleod, Norma (Box 4)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 4)
      - 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - McCulloh, Judith (Box 4)
      - General (Box 4)
        - 1961-1977 (Box 4)
        - 1964-1977 (Box 4)
        - 1977-1991 (Box 4)
      - From Latin America, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - McDowell, John H., 1988-1995 (Box 4)
    - McLean, Mervyn, 1968-1975 (Box 5)
    - M (Box 5)
      - 1958-1976 (Box 5)
      - 1978-1991 (Box 5)
    - Magoutas, Katherine, 1969-1975 (Box 5)
    - Mahmoud, Parviz, 1957-1960 (Box 5)
    - Mariño, Carmen N. de., 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    - Márquez Yañez, Francisco, 1966-1975 (Box 5)
    - Marshall, Christopher, 1971-1979 (Box 5)
    - Marulanda, Octavio, 1964-1971 (Box 5)
    - Masaya, Diane, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
    - Mason, Wilton, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Matesky, 1967-1980 (Box 5)
    - Maultsby, Portia, 1970-1976 (Box 5)
    - May, Phyllis, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Medeiros, Maria, 1971-1981 (Box 5)
    - Memberships, 1961-1976 (Box 5)
    - Merino de Zela, Mildred, 1967-1969 (Box 5)
    - Merriam, Alan, 1962-1980 (Box 5)
    - Merritt, Dean Lynne L. (Box 5)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 5)
      - 1965-1970 (Box 5)
    - Meserve, Walter, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Mexico (Box 5)
      - General, 1979-1982 (Box 5)
      - Seminar Proposals, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Miami University (Box 5)
      - General, 1992 (Box 5)
      - Lecture, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - Mini University, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - Minnesota Science Museum, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Mola, Padre Jaime Manuel, 1966-1969 (Box 5)
    - Morehouse, Ward, 1959-1964 (Box 5)
    - Srta Inés Muriel, 1969-1972 (Box 5)
    - Murray, Mr. Jim, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Musée de l'Homme, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Museum I.U. Musical Instruments, 1965-1968 (Box 5)
    - Music in the Americas (copies sent), 1967 (Box 5)
    - Music Library (Box 5)
      - 1968-1971 (Box 5)
      - 1989 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1984 (Box 5)
    - Music, School of, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - N (Box 5)
      - 1961-1972 (Box 5)
      - 1978-1988 (Box 5)
    - Najam, Edward, 1966-1973 (Box 5)
    - National Music Council, 1958-1966 (Box 5)
    - Neal, Homer, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Néprajzi Múzeum Könyvtára, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Nettl, Bruno, 1967-1975 (Box 5)
    - News Bureau, 1963-1974 (Box 5)
    - New Years Cards (Box 5)
      - General (Box 5)
        - 1960 (Box 5)
        - 1961 (Box 5)
        - 1962 (Box 5)
        - 1963 (Box 5)
        - 1964 (Box 5)
        - 1965 (Box 5)
        - 1966 (Box 5)
        - 1967 (Box 5)
      - Misc. - Instruments, 1964-1969 (Box 5)
    - New Year's Letter, 2001 (Box 5)
    - O (Box 5)
      - 1943-1969 (Box 5)
      - 1972-1977 (Box 5)
      - 1977-1994 (Box 5)
    - Olsen, Poul Rovsing, 1962-1976 (Box 5)
    - O'Neil, Robert M., 1976 (Box 5)
    - Orr, Carolyn, 1966-1976 (Box 5)
    - Orrego-Salas, Juan, 1962-1975 (Box 5)
    - Oxford University Press, 1969 (Box 5)
    - P (Box 5)
      - 1958-1973 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1993 (Box 5)
    - Parker, Franklin, 1982; 1990 (Box 5)
    - Pasqualino, Antonio, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Patekar, B.V., 1967 (Box 5)
    - Pendragon, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
    - Perdomo Escobar, Padre José Ignacio, Colombia, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Permissions, Evitar, 1979-1982 (Box 5)
    - Perry, Bernard, IU Press, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Peters, Annamay, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    - Peterson, Thesis, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Petrovic, Radmila, 1972-1976 (Box 5)
    - Photos for I.A. Brochure, 1991; undated (Box 5)
      (18 photographs and negatives removed)
    - Photos, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
      (9 photographs and negative removed)
    - Pineda, Mr. Josafat Roel, 1961-1977 (Box 5)
    - Pitro, Jiri, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Pitts, Walter, 1978-1988 (Box 5)
    - Pittsburg, University of, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Placement Bureau - School of Music, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Pramoj, Mom Rajawongse Kukrit, undated (Box 5)
    - Price, Dr. Thomas J., 1968 (Box 5)
    - Promotion and Tenure Procedures, 1970 (Box 5)
    - R (Box 5)
      - 1958-1981 (Box 5)
      - 1968-1994 (Box 5)
    - Ramón y Rivera, Luis Felipe, 1965-1979 (Box 5)
    - Raymonde, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Registrar, 1968-1975 (Box 5)
    - Requests to Publish/Contribute, 1969-1973 (Box 5)
    - Retirement, Early, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Revista Musical Chilena, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - Rhodes, Willard, 1962-1971 (Box 5)
    - Richmond, W. Edson, 1960-1975 (Box 5)
    - Rihtman, Cvjetko, 1961-1968 (Box 5)
    - Répertoire International de Littérature Musicale (RILM), 1977 (Box 5)
    - Robertson, Carole, 1970; 1975 (Box 5)
    - Rossen, Jane, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
    - Rouget, Gilbert, 1970; 1972 (Box 5)
    - Rubin, Mrs. Ruth, 1957-1959 (Box 5)
    - S, 1959-1979 (Box 5)
    - Sacks, Nahoma, 1972-1978 (Box 5)
    - Safety Division, 1958; 1965; 1974 (Box 5)
    - Scheck, Wayne, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Schmidt, Hilda, 1958 (Box 5)
    - Schroeter, Sheridan, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
    - Schwartz, Deborah, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Schwarz, Jean, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Seeger, Charles, 1957-1977 (Box 6)
    - Seully, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Sewell, Helen Johnson, 1962-1972 (Box 6)
    - Shoemaker, Raymond, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Silver Burdett Company, 1969-1973 (Box 6)
    - Simmons, Merle E., 1963-1976 (Box 6)
    - Simonson, Emma, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
    - Singer, Roberta, 1976-1983 (Box 6)
    - Smith, Ronald, 1971-1980 (Box 6)
    - Sol, Raymond, 1976-1987 (Box 6)
    - Solomon, Alexander, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Solothurmann, Jurg, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Sordo Sodi, Carmen, 1967-1972 (Box 6)
    - Sörensen, Steinar A., 1969 (Box 6)
    - Southern, Professor Eileen, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Sowanda, Fela, 1957-1965 (Box 6)
    - Speer, 1965-1985 (Box 6)
    - Spivacke, Dr. Harold, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Staff, Cards, etc., 1967-1971; undated (Box 6)
    - Stockmann, Erich, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
    - Stone, Ruth, 1971-1976 (Box 6)
    - Suchoff, Benjamin, 1961-1974 (Box 6)
    - Summer Linguistic Institute, 1963-1974 (Box 6)
    - Sykes, James, 1971 (Box 6)
    - T, 1949-1977 (Box 6)
    - Tadlock, Paula, 1975; 1979 (Box 6)
    - Tarcan, Halûk, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Teach, Carole, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Tejada, Leonardo, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
    - Thompson, John M., 1966-1967 (Box 6)
    - Translations (Box 6)
      - French, 1958-1962 (Box 6)
      - German, 1958-1964 (Box 6)
      - Misc., 1958-1963 (Box 6)
    - Travel – University, 1957-1976 (Box 6)
    - Trustees, Indiana University, 1969 (Box 6)
    - U, 1958 (Box 6)
    - V, 1961-1975 (Box 6)
    - Valdman, Albert, 1966 (Box 6)
    - van Oven, Cootje (Box 6)
      - 1969-1973 (Box 6)
        (13 photographs and negatives removed)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 6)
      - Sierra Leone, 1966-1973 (Box 6)
    - Vaughan, James, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Vazsonyi, Andrew, 1968-1973 (Box 6)
    - Viernes, Joy M., 1970; 1976 (Box 6)
    - Visiting Scholar, etc., 1974 (Box 6)
    - Voegelin, Carl, 1957-1962 (Box 6)
    - W, 1958-1978 (Box 6)
    - Wachsmann, Klaus, 1961-1975 (Box 6)
    - Ward, John, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Warrell, Sue, 1945-1947 (Box 6)
      (17 photographs and negative removed)
    - Waterman, Richard, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Wells, Chancellor Herman B, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Wenker, Jerome, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
    - Whitten, Norman E., 1964 (Box 6)
    - Wilgus, Dr. D.K., 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    - Winkelman, Donald, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
    - Wirt, Monica, 1968-1974 (Box 6)
    - World Explorers Program, 1966 (Box 6)
    - World Tape Pals, Inc., 1957-1962 (Box 6)
    - XYZ, 1962-1993 (Box 6)
    - Yassin, Mustapha Kamil, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Youngblood, Joseph, 1960; 1968 (Box 6)
    - Yurchenko, Henrietta Mrs. S., 1966-1973 (Box 6)
    - Zablodowsky, Gen, David and Wanda, 1933-1985 (Box 6)
      - 1933-1971 (Box 6)
      - 1969-1985 (Box 6)
      - 1971-1974 (Box 6)
      - 1971-1976 (Box 6)
      - 1977-1984 (Box 6)
    - Zapata Olivella, Delia, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Lecture – Delia Zapata, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Zapata Olivella, Delia, 1964-1973 (Box 6)
    - Zapata, Manuel, 1964-1976 (Box 6)
    - Zapata, 1966-1996 (Box 6)
    - Zapata NSF Grant, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Zapata, Personal, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Zapata Professional, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
    - De Zárate, Profesora Dora P., 1968-1969 (Box 6)
- Publications, 1946-2005; undated (Box 7)
  - Monographs, 1968-1994; undated (Box 7)
    - Evitar Book (Box 7)
      - Evitar: Children's Games Caballero, 1968 (Box 7)
      - Originals (Box 7)
        - Chapters 5-6, undated (Box 7)
        - Chapters 7-8, undated (Box 7)
        - Chapters 9-10, undated (Box 7)
        - Chapters 11-13, undated (Box 7)
    - Cantos Costeños (Box 7)
      - Cantos Costeños, 1973 (Box 7)
      - General, 1973 (Box 7)
      - Second Revision, undated (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
      - Contract, 1974 (Box 7)
      - Photographs for Cantos Costeños, undated (Box 7)
        (4 photographs and negative removed)
    - Cuentos Costeños (unpublished) (Box 7)
      - List of Cuentos, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Cuentos: Tale Type, Indexes, Etc., 1991 (Box 7)
      - Mártara Story, undated (Box 7)
      - Manuscript, 1994 (Box 7)
      - Copy, undated (Box 7)
      - Manuscript, George List and Hasan El-Shamy, undated (Box 7)
  - Articles and chapters, 1946-2005 (Box 7)
    - Article 1: "American Songs for the Chinese," Triad, 1946 (Box 7)
    - Article 2: "A Basic Philosophy for the Teaching of Music Theory"American Music Teacher, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Article 3: "An Ideal Marriage of Ballad Text and Tune," Midwest Folklore, Dissertation Abstract, Dissertation Abstracts, 1957; 1954 (Box 7)
    - Article 4: "A Short History of the Cylinder Phonograph"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Article 5: "The Reproduction of Cylinder Recordings"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1958-59 (Box 7)
    - Article 6: "The Indiana University Archives of Folk and Primitive Music"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1959-60 (Box 7)
    - Article 7: "Documenting Sound Recordings"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Article 8: "Speech Melody and Song Melody in Central Thailand"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Article 9: "Archiving Sound Recordings"Phonetica, 1961 (Box 7)
    - Article 10: "Song in Hopi Culture, Past and Present"Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Article 11: "Ethnomusicology in Higher Education"Music Journal, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Article 12: "The Practice and Preservation of Traditional Music"The Journal of the Music Academy, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Article 13: "The Boundaries of Speech and Song"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Article 14: "An Approach to the Indexing of Ballad Tunes"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Article 15: "The Musical Significance of Transcription"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Article 16: "Techniques for Dance Ethnology in Television and Film"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Article 17: "The Hopi and the White Man's Music"Sing Out, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Article 18: "Music in the Culture of the Jíbaro Indians of the Ecuadorian Montaña"Inter-American Music Bulletin, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Article 19: "Acculturation and Musical Tradition"Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Article 20: "Impresiones de Etnomusicología y Folklore en América Latina"Revista Musical Chilena, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Article 21: Contribution to "Symposium on Transcription and Analysis"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Article 22: "Folksongs of the Maine Woods, Annotated Transcriptions"The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Article 23: "Ethnomusicology in Colombia"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Article 24: "Ethnomusicology in Ecuador"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Article 25: "Folksongs from Michigan, from the Repertoire of J.B. Suggs, etc."The Folklore and Folk Music Archivist, 1966-67 (Box 7)
    - Article 26: "The Musical Bow at Palenque"Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Article 27: "Recordings for Research"The Review, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Article 28: "The Folk Music of the Atlantic Coast of Colombia, An Introduction"Music in the Americas, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Article 29: "South America"Keyboard Junior, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Article 30: "Music of Spain"Keyboard Junior, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Article 31: "Toward the Indexing of Ballad Texts"Journal of American Folklore, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Article 32: "The Mbira in Cartagena"Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Article 33: "The Hopi as Composer and Poet"Proceedings of the Centennial Workshop in Ethnomusicology etc., 1968 (Box 7)
    - Article 34: "A Statement on Archiving"Journal of the Folklore Institute Vol. VI, Nos. 2/3m pp.222-231, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Article 35: "On the Non-Universality of Musical Perspectives"Ethnomusicology Vol. 15, No. 2 p. 399-402, (May 1971) (Box 7)
    - Article 36: "El Conjunto de Gaitas de Colombia, la Herencia de Tres Culturas"Revista Musical Chilena Vol. XXVII, No. 123-24, Julio-Diciembre pp. 43-54, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Article 36: "El Conjunto de Gaitas de Colombia, la Herencia de Tres Culturas"Revista Musical Chilena Vol. XXVII, No. 123-24, Julio-Diciembre pp. 43-54, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Article 37: "A Comparison of Certain Aspects of Colombian and Spanish Folksong"Yearbook of the International Folk Music Council Vol. 5, pp. 72-84, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Article 38: "The Reliability of Transcription"Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology Vol. XVII, No. 3, Sept., 1974 (Box 7)
    - Article 39: "Musical Concepts in Traditional Cultures"Folklore in America Linda Degh, Henry Glassie, and Felix Oinas, eds. Research Center in the Language Sciences, Indiana University, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Article 40: "Transcripción de la Música Tradicional"Revista INDEF Venezuela, Vol. 2, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Article 41: "The Distribution of a Melodic Formula: Diffusion or Polygenesis?" Yearbook of the International Folk Music Council Vol. 10, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Article 42: "Ethnomusicology: A Discipline Defined"Ethnomusicology Vol. XXIII, No. 1, January 1979 (Box 8)
    - Article 43: "African Influences in the Rhythmic and Metric Organization of Colombian Folk Song and Folk Music"Latin American Music Review, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Article 44: "Colombia II. Folk Music"New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Article 45: "A Secular Sermon for Those of the Ethnomusicological Faith," revised version of address given at the 27th Annual Meeting of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Article 46: "Concerning the Concept of the Universal and Music"The World of Music Vol. XXVI, No. 2, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Article 47: "Hopi Melodic Concepts"Journal of the American Musicological Society Vol. 38, No. 1, Spring, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Original Photos and Negatives of Melographs for Article "Hopi Melodic Concepts", 1985 (Box 8)
    - Article 48: "Stability and Variation in a Hopi Lullaby"Ethnomusicology Volume 31, Number 1, Winter, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Article 49: "Traditional Children's Songs and Singing Games from Southern Indiana"Midwestern Folklore, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Article 50: "Two Flutes and a Rattle: The Evolution of an Ensemble"Musical Quarterly, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Article 51: "How a Hopi Woman Made Pottery"School Arts 91 (6) (Feb. 1992). Hopi Pottery Article, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Article 52: "Basing a Book on the Archives' Collections"Resound 11(3) (July 1992). Répertoire International de la Littérature Musicale (RILM) Abstract for "Music and Poetry in a Colombian Village: A Tri-Cultural History,", 1988 (Box 8)
    - "Conjunto de Gaitas," English version (not published), 1976 (Box 8)
    - Tone vs. Tune (semi?) Final, undated (Box 8)
    - Speech/Music Permissions, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Earlier Drafts of Parallelism Article, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
    - Parallelism Article - Final Printout, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Bailes Costeños Revised Ver. 2, 1991; 1995 (Box 8)
    - "Basing a Book on the Archives' Collections," Ver. 1 and 2, 1992; undated (Box 8)
    - "Some Comments on Class Instruction in the Transcription of Traditional Music"Resound, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Publication, 1999-2000 (Box 8)
    - Introduction to "The Function and Organization of a Folklore Archive," New Grove Dictionary of Music and Muscians, 1999-2000 (Box 8)
    - Article in Folklore Historian "The Function and Organization of a Folklore Archive,", 2002 (Box 8)
    - Publishing, 2005 (Box 8)
    - Mozart and Tonality Correspondence, 2005 (Box 8)
    - Mozart and Tonality Manuscript, 2005 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 1: "Folk Music" in Richard M. Dorson, ed.Folklore and Folklife, an Introduction, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 2: "Fieldwork: Recording Traditional Music," in R.M. Dorson, ed.Folklore and Folklife, an Introduction, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 3: "Archiving," in Richard M. Dorson, ed.Folklore and Folklife, an Introduction, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Reviews, 1959-1993 (Box 8)
    - Review 1: Jewish Life and Yiddish Folk Songs, in Journal of American Folklore, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Review 2: Preservation and Storage of Recordings, in Journal of American Folklore, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Review 3: Folksingers and Folksongs, in Journal of Southern History, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Review 4: More Traditional Ballads of Virginia, in Journal of Southern History, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Review 5: Cheremis Musical Styles, in Western Folklore, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Review 6: The Music of Afghanistan, in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Review 7: Burut Music of North Borneo, in Journal of American Folklore, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Review 8: Music of the Pueblos, Apache, and Navaho, in Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Review 9: Rites of the Pagan, Realm of the Incas, in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Review 10: Carvalho Neto, Paulo de, Diccionario del Folklore Ecuatoriano, in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Review 11: Instruments and Music of Bolivia in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Review 12: Inter-American Institute for Musical Research, Yearbook, in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Review 13: Hopi Katcina Songs, etc., in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Review 14: Aretz, Isabel, "La Etnomusicología en Venezuela, etc." in Journal of the International Folk Music Council, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Review 15: Traditional Chilean Songs and The Piñata Party Presents Music of Perú in Journal of American Folklore, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Review 16: Frisbie, Charlotte Johnson, Kinaaldá, etc., in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Review 17: Afro-Hispanic Music from Western Colombia and Ecuador, in Journal of the Society for Ethnomusicology, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Review 18: Nettl, Bruno, "Folk and Traditional Music of the Western Continents," in Western Folklore, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Review 19: Music of Guatemala, Jacques Jangouy, Asch Mankind Series, Ethnomusicology, XV, 2 p. 323, May 1971 (Box 8)
    - Review 20: (Film Review) Hopi: Songs of the Fourth World. Ferrero Films, San Francisco. J. Society for Ethnomusicology Vol. 30, No. 1, Winter, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Reviews for Dorson, 1959-1967 (Box 8)
    - Review for Dorson -- Nettl, Cheremis, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Reviews of My Publications, 1961 (Box 8)
    - Reviews for Sebeok, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Review -- University of North Carolina Press, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Review -- Song Tradition of Tristan Da Cunha, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Cantos Costeños Reviews, 1974-1976 (Box 8)
    - Reviews: Singing About it: Folk Song in Southern Indiana, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Reviews: Stability and Variation in Hopi Song, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Reviews - My Book, 1983-1992 (Box 8)
- Research, 1894; 1953-2006; undated (Box 9)
  - Bibliography (Box 9)
    - General, 2005-2006 (Box 9)
    - Mozart and Tonality, undated (Box 9)
  - Book: Music and drawings (Box 9)
    - Plates, full set (copies), undated (Box 9)
    - 2nd Question Copies of Drawings, undated (Box 9)
  - Children Catalog Bloomington, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Colombian Catalogues, Extra Copies, 1964-1968 (Box 9)
  - Extra Copies of Books for Colombian Music, undated, contains negatives, (oversize) (Box 9)
  - Folklore Library (Box 9)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 9)
    - 1968-1975 (Box 9)
  - Hopi Catalog, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Hopi References, undated (Box 9)
  - Index Cards (2 sets), undated (Box 18 Oversize)
  - Indonesian Catalog, 1987 (Box 9)
  - New York City - AFS, SEM Photo research NY Public Library NBC Film Library, December 1958 (Box 9)
  - Northern Arizona Hopi Catalog, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Speech and Song Project Research (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody General, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Song Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody Preliminary Manuscript, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody 1st Print-Out, 12 July 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Song Project Bibliographies, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Song Project Proposal/Bibliography, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody Drum and other Language Surrogates, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody Americas Including Amerindians, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Melody African Languages, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Language Oriental Languages, undated (Box 9)
    - Austerlitz Articles, undated (Box 9)
    - Pitts, Walter, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    - Speech/Song Kuhils Bibliographies, undated (Box 9)
    - Phonetic Alphabet, undated (Box 9)
    - Speech/Song Project Notes/Queries, undated (Box 9)